Register to The David Kraehenbuehl Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Music, Series I
  - Music by David Kraehenbuehl
    - Orchestral and Band Works, I.B
      - Toccata sinfonica / David Kraehenbuehl. -- c.1983 by Symphony School of America., 1 manuscript score (26 p.); 28 cm. (Box 3, Folder 26)
        In envelope (discarded) marked: for Sym School of America.
      - [Variation suite, piano, string orchestra] Variation suite / David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (64 p.) + 5 parts (35 p. total); 35 cm. (Box 3, Folder 27)
        For piano solo, violin I, violin II, viola, violoncello, double bass.
        At end: Colorado Springs, 20 June 1951.
      - [Variation suite, piano, string orchestra] Variation suite / David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (64 p.) + 5 parts (35 p. total); 35 cm. (Box 3, Folder 27)
        Photocopy of holograph, annotations in pencil and ink.
      - [Variation suite, piano, string orchestra; arr.] Variation suite / David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (43 p.); 32 cm. (Box 3, Folder 28)
      - [Variation suite, piano, string orchestra; arr.] Variation suite / David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript part (15 p.); 32 cm. (Box 3, Folder 29)
        Holograph in ink, annotations in pencil and ink.
        Part for piano II.
    - Chamber Works, I.C
      - Ash Wednesday: a commentary for cello and piano after a poem by T. S. Eliot / by David Kraehenbuehl. -- 1966., 1 manuscript score (28 p.) + 1 part (9 p.); 35 cm. (Box 3, Folder 30)
        I. Ritornello...Because I do not hope... -- II. Rondo...Lady, three white leopards... -- III. Recitative -- Arioso...At the first turning... -- IV. Aria...Who walked... -- V. Variations...If the lost word... -- VI. Ritornello...Although I do not hope...
        On title page: Commissioned by the Kindler Foundation, Duration: 21 minutes approx.
        At end: Princeton, N.J., July 9, 1966.
      - Ash Wednesday: a commentary for cello and piano after a poem by T. S. Eliot / by David Kraehenbuehl. -- 1966., 1 manuscript score (28 p.) 28 cm. (Box 3, Folder 30)
        Photocopy of holograph, annotations in pencil and colored pencil.
      - Ash Wednesday: a commentary for cello and piano after the poem of T. S. Eliot / by David Kraehenbuehl. -- c.1995 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 score (42 p.) + 1 part (18 p.); 28 cm. (Box 3, Folder 30)
        At end: Total time: 21' 15"
        Program note and biographical note printed on the score.
      - [Canzonas, flute, oboe, clarinet, bassoon] Canzona: for woodwind quartet / David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (14 p.) + 4 manuscript parts (12 p. total); 35 cm. (Box 3, Folder 31)
        Holograph in ink, annotations in pencil and colored pencil, some cut-outs.
        At end: New Haven, Conn., August 21, 1953, Revised: Jan. 24, 1954, to the Yale Woodwind Quartet, Shirley Williams, Allen Williams, Keith Wilson, Paul Tucci.
        In envelope (discarded) marked: reworked 1995 for string quartet.
      - [Canzonas, string quartet] Canzona for string quartet / by David Kraehenbuehl. -- c.1995 by David Kraehenbuehl [pasted over], 1 score (22 p.) + 2 parts (7 p. total); 28 cm. (Box 3, Folder 32)
        "Written for the Artaria Quartet of Boston in grateful appreciation for their sensitive and brilliant premier performance of my first string quartet, Pas des Papillons, May 27, 1995 at Viterbo College in La Crosse, Wisconsin."
        Program note printed on the score.
        Only the viola part and p.1 of the violin I part are present.
      - Ceremonial music: for brass quintet / by David Kraehenbuehl. -- The Kramm Library, c.1995., 1 score (6 p.); 28 cm. (Box 3, Folder 33)
        On cover: (1971)
      - [Diptych, violin, piano] Diptych: for violin and piano / David Kraehenbuehl. -- New York: Associated Music Publishers, c.1955., 1 score (38 p.) + 1 part (12 p.); 31 cm. (Box 3, Folder 34)
        Annotations in pencil and ink.
        I. Canzona di Dionigi -- II. Partita d'Apollone.
        "To Frank Costanzo."
        At end: Colorado Springs, May 1953.
        2 copies, 1 copy of score and part are photocopies.
        In envelope (discarded) marked: Sarabande, 2nd movement, used for harp & orchestra, Sym. School of America, 1979.
      - Epithalamion 1941 / David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (4 p.); 28 cm. (Box 3, Folder 35)
        For violin and cello.
        At end: Composed for Dan and Ruth Hayes in celebration of their golden wedding anniversary, August 10, 1991.
      - [Kaleidoscope; arr.] Kaleidoscope: movements for clarinet, viola, and piano / by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (18 p.) + 2 manuscript parts (8 p. total); 35 cm. (Box 3, Folder 36)
        On title page: Written for Robert Henderson.
        At end: Princeton, New Jersey, March, 1962.
        In envelope (discarded) marked: See Kaleidoscope for Orchestra (1958)
      - Line drawings: clarinet solo / David Kraehenbuehl. -- c.1959 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (2 p.); 35 cm. (Box 3, Folder 37)
        Holograph in ink, annotations in pencil.
        Incomplete, lacks p. 3.
      - Line drawings: clarinet solo / David Kraehenbuehl. -- c.1959 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (2 p.); 35 cm. (Box 3, Folder 37)
        At end: New Haven, Conn., December 22, 1958.
      - Line drawings: for solo clarinet / by David Kraehenbuehl. -- c.1959 by Earl M. Banquer., 1 manuscript score (6 p.); 28 cm. (Box 3, Folder 37)
        Photocopy of copyist's manuscript.
        On title page: For Earl Banquer.
        Edition prepared by Earl Banquer?
      - Line drawings: a set of five pieces for solo clarinet / by David Kraehenbuehl. -- c.1995 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 score (9 p.); 28 cm. (Box 3, Folder 37)
      - Lyric etudes / David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (38 p.) + 6 manuscript parts; 44 cm. (Box 16, Folder 231)
        Score lacks p. 11-17 (movement II), part of p. 22 removed.
        Some corrections taped in.
        For violin (clarinet 1), viola (clarinet 2), violoncello (bassoon), and keyboard [i.e. harpsichord]
        I. Sonata. -- II. Notturno. -- III. Partita. -- IV. Moto perpetuo.
        At end: To Robert Conant, eminent harpsichordist, August 29, 1956.
      - Lyric etudes / David Kraehenbuehl., 6 manuscript parts; 43 cm. (Box 16, Folder 231)
      - Metamorphosis: for clarinet and piano / David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (20 p.); 36 cm. (Box 3, Folder 38)
        At end: July 29, 1954, New Haven, Conn.
        2 copies.
      - Pas des papillons: for string quartet / by David Kraehenbuehl. / c.1994 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 score (30 p.); 28 cm. (Box 3, Folder 39)
        I. Danse de jeune amour. -- II. Danse de tristesse. -- III. Danses d'E. et F. -- IV. Danse de démence et mort.
      - [Quintets, oboe, clarinet, bassoon, horn, piano] Wind quintet / Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (64 p.) + 4 manuscript parts (24 p. total); 35 cm. (Box 3, Folder 40)
        I. Scherzo. -- II. Variations. -- III. Fugue.
        Variations based on a theme from Ludus Tonalis by Paul Hindemith.
        In envelope (discarded) marked: 1949
      - Scherzo, Variations, & Fugue
        see [Quintets, oboe, clarinet, bassoon, horn, piano]
      - Seascape / David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (9 p.) + 3 manuscript parts (5 p. total); 28 cm. (Box 3, Folder 41)
        For violin, harp, and piano.
        At end: For the Helbig family, April 6, 1961, Princeton, N.J.
      - [Sonata da chiesa, oboe, violoncello, harpsichord], 1 manuscript part (6 p.); 35 cm. (Box 3, Folder 42)
        I. Aria. -- II. Fugue. -- Ground. -- IV. Concerto.
        Oboe part only, other parts lacking.
      - String Quartet no. 1
        see: Pas des papillons
      - Triptych: for brass octet / David Kraehenbuehl. -- c.1994 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 score (36 p.) + 8 parts (32 p. total); 22 x 28 cm. and 28 cm. (Box 3, Folder 43)
        For trumpet I, trumpet II, cornet, horn I, horn II, trombone I, trombone II, tuba.
        I. Left Panel. -- II. Center Panel. -- III. Right Panel.
        Program note printed on score.
        On title page: 1952.
      - Variations on a pavane for krummhorns by Hermann Schein: for clarinet quartet or choir / David Kraehenbuehl. -- New York: Associated Music Publishers, c.1951., 1 score (12 p.) + 4 parts (17 p. total): 30 cm. (Box 3, Folder 44)
        For clarinets in B I, II, III, and bass clarinet.
      - [Variations on a pavane for krummhorns by Hermann Schein] Variations on a baroque dance / David Kraehenbuehl. -- c.1995 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 score (11 p.); 28 cm. (Box 3, Folder 44)
        For clarinets in Bb I, II, III, and bass clarinet.
    - Keyboard Music, I.D
      - [Concert of the humours; arr.] A concert of the humours / David Kraehenbuehl., 2 manuscript scores (total 36 p.); 35 cm. (Box 3, Folder 45)
        At end: August 26, 1962, Princeton, N.J.
      - [Diptych, piano] Diptych: for solo piano / by David Kraehenbuehl. -- c.1951 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 score (23 p.); 28 cm. (Box 3, Folder 46)
        I. Variations. -- II. Quickmarch.
      - [Diptyque, piano] Diptyque for solo piano (1951): from The collected works for solo piano / David Kraehenbuehl; edited by Martha Braden. -- New York: Martha Braden, c.1999 by Martha Braden., 1 score (25 p.); 29 cm. (Box 3, Folder 46)
        Program notes printed on the score.
        Gift of Martha Braden.
      - Ephemera: piano solo / David Kraehenbuehl. -- c.1962 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (5 p.); 35 cm. (Box 4, Folder 47)
        I. Elegy. -- II. Epigram. -- III. Enigma. -- IV. Epitaph.
        At end: Princeton, N.J., September, 1962.
      - Fanfares: variations for piano solo / by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (7 p.); 28 cm. (Box 4, Folder 48)
        On title page: Commissioned by the Unitarian Church of Princeton for the Dedication of the Church Community Center, September 22, 1968.
        At end: Cranbury, N.J., August 31, 1968. Duration: 5 1/4' approx.
      - A formal triad: for piano solo / by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (11 p.); 35 cm. (Box 4, Folder 49)
        I. s/s -- II. d/d -- III. s/d
        At end: To Armin Watkins, in grateful appreciation of his devotion to my concerto for piano. David Kraehenbuehl. August 18, 1958, New Haven, Conn.
      - A formal triad (1958): from The collected works for solo piano / David Kraehenbuehl; edited by Martha Braden. -- New York: Martha Braden, c.1999 by Martha Braden., 1 score (p. 59-74); 29 cm. (Box 4, Folder 49)
      - [Looking back] Peter's tune / David Kraehenbuehl., 1 score (18 p.); 29 cm. (Box 4, Folder 50)
        Photocopy.
        Peter's Tune. -- A Strange Procession. -- The Old Organgrinder. -- The Sad Cuckoo. -- Peter in the Rain. -- Castles in the Air. -- Peter Doesn't Like It. -- Round Dance. -- Follow Peter. -- Goldfish in the Sun. -- Free-for-All. -- Peter's Lullaby.
        At end: March, 1954.
      - Looking back: twelve images from my past for any keyboard instrument / by David Kraehenbuehl. -- c.1994 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 score (27 p.); 28 cm. (Box 4, Folder 50)
        Peter's Tune. -- A Strange Procession. -- The Old Organgrinder. -- Sad Cuckoo. -- Playing in the Rain. -- Castles in the Air. -- Tantrum. -- Round and Round. -- Follow the Leader. -- Goldfish in the Sun. -- Roughhouse. -- Falling Asleep.
        On title page: 1954.
      - Looking back (1954): from The collected works for solo piano / David Kraehenbuehl; edited by Martha Braden. -- New York: Martha Braden, c.1999 by Martha Braden., 1 score (p. 105-130); 29 cm. (Box 4, Folder 50)
      - [Piano music. Selections] The collected works for solo piano / David Kraehenbuehl; edited by Martha Braden. -- New York: Martha Braden, c.1999 by Martha Braden., 1 score (130 p.); 29 cm. (Box 4, Folder 51)
        Diptych. -- Toccate per Cembalo. -- A Formal Triad. -- Toccata sopra B-A-C-H. -- Random Walks. -- Looking Back: Twelve Images from My Past.
        Program notes printed at the end of each work.
      - [Piano music. Selections. Rev. ed.]
        see: Series X, Additions
      - Random walks (1962-1966): from The collected works for solo piano / David Kraehenbuehl; edited by Martha Braden. -- New York: Martha Braden, c.1999 by Martha Braden., 1 score (p. 95-104); 29 cm. (Box 4, Folder 52)
      - Sonata for piano / David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (21 p.); 31 cm. (Box 4, Folder 53)
        Holograph in ink and pencil, annotations in ink, pencil and colored pencil.
        Dated April 29, 1943 (movement 1), July 10, 1943 (movement 2), movement 3 undated.
      - Sonatine balletique: for piano four-hands / by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (29 p.); 35 cm. (Box 4, Folder 54)
        I. Scènes militaires. -- II. Pas de deux. -- III. Chevaux de bois.
        On title page: Duration: Approx. 16'
        At end: Cranbury, N.J., February 22, 1967.
      - Sonatine balletique: for piano four-hands / by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (29 p.); 35 cm. (Box 4, Folder 54)
      - [Toccatas, harpsichord] Toccate per cembalo (1955): from The collected works for solo piano / David Kraehenbuehl; edited by Martha Braden. -- New York: Martha Braden, c.1999 by Martha Braden., 1 score (p. 27-57); 29 cm. (Box 4, Folder 55)
      - Toccata sopra B-A-C-H (1985): from The collected works for solo piano / David Kraehenbuehl; edited by Martha Braden. -- New York: Martha Braden, c.1999 by Martha Braden., 1 score (p. 75-93); 29 cm. (Box 4, Folder 56)
      - [Trios, organ], 1 manuscript score (11 p.); 29 cm. (Box 4, Folder 57)
        3 trios for organ: Spiritoso, Semplice (Pastorale), Amabile.
        Scores were together, but order uncertain, and also whether the three pieces constitute one work.
        At end of Amabile: Cranbury, N.J., 3/17/73.
    - Choral Music, I.E
      - [Variation suite, piano (4 hands)] Variation suite for piano 4-hands / David Kraehenbuehl., 4 manuscript scores (15 + 19 + 12 + 16 p.); 35 cm. (Box 4, Folder 58)
        I. Circus Overture. -- II. Pastorale and Scherzo. -- III. Elegy and Lament. -- IV. March and Finale.
        At end: Colorado Springs, March 21, 1953.
      - [Variation suite, piano (4 hands)] Variation suite for piano 4-hands / David Kraehenbuehl., 3 manuscript scores (15 + 19 + 12 p.); 35 cm. (Box 4, Folder 58)
        Lacks movement IV, 2 copies of movement II.
      - Advent tropes / by David Kraehenbuehl. -- c1983., 1 manuscript score (65 p.); 43 cm. (Box 17, Folder 232)
        Holograph in ink, corrections pasted in and written over liquid paper.
        For SATB chorus and instrumental ensemble.
        Introduction. -- Trope I: O Wisdom of the Most High God. -- Trope II: O Lord of Israel. -- Trope III: O Flow'r of Jerusalem. -- Trope IV: O Key of David. -- Trope V: O Daystar. -- Trope VI: O Desired One of the Nations. -- Trope VII: O Emmanuel. -- Conclusion.
        On cover: Commissioned by and written for the Music Department of Viterbo College, La Crosse, Wisconsin.
        At end: Total time: 34' 00", September 29, 1983, La Crosse, Wisconsin, Laus Deo!
      - Advent tropes / by David Kraehenbuehl. -- c1983., 1 manuscript score (65 p.); 28 cm. (Box 4, Folder 59)
        At end: Total time: 34' 00", September 29, 1983, La Crosse, Wisonsin, Laus Deo!
      - [Advent tropes], 1 manuscript score (pp. 2-37); 22 x 28 cm. (Box 4, Folder 59)
        Short score on 4-5 staves.
        At end: Total performance time: 34' 00", September 4, 1983, La Crosse, Wisconsin.
      - Allô-adieu.
        see: [Chansons. Allô-adieu]
      - [Appalachian elegy. Vocal score] Appalachian elegy: based on the poem "My father": for treble choir and piano / text Goff Owen, Sr.; music David Kraehenbuehl. -- c.1978 by David Kraehenbuehl, text used by permission of Goff Owen, Jr., 1 manuscript score (15 p.); 35 cm. (Box 4, Folder 60)
        Arr. for SSA chorus and piano.
        Text printed on p. 3.
        On title page: Written for Frances Slade and the Princeton Pro Musica [taped onto title page]
        On title page: Commissioned by Goff Owen, Jr.
        At end: Cranbury, N.J., October 8, 1978.
      - [Appalachian elegy. Vocal score] Appalachian elegy: based on the poem "My father": for treble choir and piano / text Goff Owen, Sr.; music David Kraehenbuehl. -- c.1978 by David Kraehenbuehl, text used by permission of Goff Owen, Jr., 1 manuscript score (15 p.); 35 cm. (Box 4, Folder 60)
        Scored for [SSA chorus], piano, harp, celeste, xylophone, timpani, chime.
        On title page: Written for Donald Hanson and the Columbus Boychoir.
      - [Appalachian elegy. Vocal score] Appalachian elegy: based on the poem "My father": for treble choir and piano or pitched percussion / text Goff Owen, Sr.; music David Kraehenbuehl. -- c.1978 by David Kraehenbuehl, text used by permission of Goff Owen, Jr., 1 manuscript score (15 p.); 28 cm. (Box 4, Folder 60)
        On title page: Written for Frances Slade and the Princeton Pro Musica ["Frances Slade" and "Princeton Pro Musica" written over liquid paper.]
        2 copies. On one tp: Rededicated to Frances Slade & the Princeton Pro Musica. Reason for the change - [Columbus] boychoir could not handle it for performance. G. O. Jr.
      - [Appalachian elegy. Choral score] Appalachian elegy: based on the poem "My father": [text by] Goff Owen, Sr.; [music by] David Kraehenbuehl. -- c.1978 by David Kraehenbuehl, text used by permission of Goff Owen, Jr., 1 manuscript score (8 p.); 28 cm. (Box 4, Folder 60)
        Score for soprano, soprano/alto, and alto.
      - [Appalachian elegy. Choral score] Appalachian elegy: based on the poem "My father": [text by] Goff Owen, Sr.; [music by] David Kraehenbuehl. -- c.1978 by David Kraehenbuehl, text used by permission of Goff Owen, Jr., 1 manuscript score (8 p.); 29 cm. (Box 4, Folder 60)
      - [Appalachian elegy. Parts] Appalachian elegy / David Kraehenbuehl., 6 manuscript parts (15 p. total); 28 cm. (Box 4, Folder 60)
        Parts for celeste, harp, pedal timpani, piano, tubular bell, xylophone.
        Gift of Goff Owen, Jr.
      - [Appalachian elegy (Sketches)] Holograph in pencil., 6 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 4, Folder 60)
      - The betrayal: a motet cycle for the Passion season / David Kraehenbuehl. -- New Haven: Kramm Library, c.1959., 3 manuscript scores (7 + 8 + 7 p.); 28 cm. (Box 4, Folder 61)
        For SATB chorus.
        At end: The Betrayal, a setting of the responses of the Tenebrae service, is dedicated to the Capella Cordina, whose members, under the direction of Donald Loach, have sung its various parts repeatedly at Christ Church, New Haven, Connecticut. March, 1957.
      - The betrayal: a motet cycle for the Passion season / David Kraehenbuehl. -- New Haven: Kramm Library, c.1959., 3 manuscript scores (7 + 8 + 7 p.); 22 cm. (Box 4, Folder 61)
      - [Chansons. Allô-adieu] Allô-adieu / David Kraehenbuehl. -- c.1968 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (2 p.); 32 cm. (Box 4, Folder 62)
        For three voices.
        Text in French.
        At end: Time: 3' 00" approx., Cranbury, N.J., 3/14/68.
      - [Chansons. Car vrayment] When you're out of sight, I'm out of my mind. -- c.1968 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (2 p.); 28 cm. (Box 4, Folder 62)
        Holograph in pencil, annotations in ink.
        Piano score with text underlay and chord symbols.
        2 copies, one copy a photocopy.
        With typescript text (1 p.) and manuscript chord symbols (1 p.)
      - [Chansons. Dolores] Dolores. -- c.1968 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (1 p.); 28 cm. (Box 4, Folder 62)
        Piano score with melody line, text underlay, and chord symbols.
        With typescript text (1 p.)
      - [Chansons. Le grant desir] Le grant desir, or The big long. -- c.1968 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (1 p.); 28 cm. (Box 4, Folder 62)
        At end: 2-5-68.
      - [Chansons. Weep willow] Weep willow / words and music David Kraehenbuehl. -- c.1967 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 manuscript score (3 p.); 31 cm. (Box 4, Folder 62)
        For voice and piano with chord symbols.
        With manuscript melody (1 p.), manuscript chord symbols (2 p.), and manuscript text (2 p.)
      - [Christmas choruses, no. 1. The star song] The star song: a Christmas chorus / [text by] Robert Herrick; [music by] David Kraehenbuehl. -- New York: Associated Music Publishers, c1954., 1 score (21 p.); 26 cm. (Box 4, Folder 63)
        For SSATB chorus a cappella, piano reduction for rehearsal only.
        Pub. no.: A-192
        Signed on inside cover: Happy Birthday, John David, 1955
      - [Christmas choruses, no. 2. Ideo gloria in excelsis deo] Ideo gloria in excelsis deo: a Christmas chorus / [text] Traditional; [music by] David Kraehenbuehl. -- New York: Associated Music Publishers, c1954., 1 score (8 p.); 26 cm. (Box 4, Folder 63)
        Pub. no.: A-193.
      - [Christmas choruses, no. 3. There is no rose] There is no rose: a Christmas chorus / [text] XVth century; [music by] David Kraehenbuehl. -- New York: Associated Music Publishers, c.1954., 1 score (8 p.); 26 cm. (Box 4, Folder 63)
        Pub. no.: A-194
      - [Christmas choruses, no. 4. A song against bores] A song against bores: a Christmas chorus / [text] XVIth century; [music by] David Kraehenbuehl. -- New York: Associated Music Publishers, c.1954., 1 score (5 p.); 26 cm. (Box 4, Folder 63)
        "The text for this choral setting was taken from a manuscript in the library of Balliol College. It is used by permission of the Master and Fellows of Balliol College."
        Pub. no.: A-195
      - City scene: for mixed chorus a cappella / by David Kraehenbuehl. -- c.1968 by Westwood Press, Cincinnati, Ohio., 1 manuscript score (13 p.); 32 cm. (Box 5, Folder 64)
        Holograph in ink, annotations in pencil, colored pencil, ink, and taped in.
        For SATB chorus, piano reduction for rehearsal only.
        Pub. no.: ESE-1485-8
        At end: Duration: 4' 30", Cranbury, N.J., January 18, 1967.
      - City scene: SATB a cappella / text and music by David Kraehenbuehl. -- Cincinnati: Westwood Press, c1968., 1 score (20 p.); 26 cm. (Box 5, Folder 64)
        Piano reduction for rehearsal only.
        Duration: 4' 30"
        (Parkway choral series)
        Pl. no.: ESE-1485-8
      - City scene: a choral ballet for SATB chorus unaccompanied / text and music by David Kraehenbuehl. -- c.1995 by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 score (13 p.); 28 cm. (Box 5, Folder 64)
        On title page: 1953.
        At end: 4' 30"
      - Dolores.
        see: [Chansons. Dolores]
      - Drumfire: a cantata against war: for mezzo-soprano and baritone, SATB chorus and orchestra / by David Kraehenbuehl; text by Goff Owen, Sr. -- c.1986 by Goff Owen, Jr., 1 manuscript score (104 p.) + 18 manuscript parts (135 p. total); 43 and 30 cm. (Box 17, Folder 233)
        Holograph in ink, corrections in liquid paper and ink.
        I. The First Horseman: Oppression. -- II. ...of the Guns. -- III. The Second Horseman: Violence. -- IV. Why is War? -- V. The Third Horseman: Famine. -- VI. 'Tis an Ungodly Blighted Hour. -- VII. The Fourth Horseman: Death. -- VIII. They Say It's Done. -- IX. Have You Heard Them?
        At end: Trempealeau, Wisconsin, January 30, 1986.
        Total duration: 35' 30"
      - Drumfire: a cantata against war: for mezzo-soprano and baritone, SATB chorus and orchestra / by David Kraehenbuehl; text by Goff Owen, Sr. -- c.1986 by Goff Owen, Jr., 1 manuscript score (104 p.); 36 cm. (Box 5, Folder 65)
      - [Drumfire. Choral score] Drumfire: a cantata against war / by David Kraehenbuehl; text by Goff Owen, Sr. -- c.1986 by Goff Owen, Jr., 1 manuscript score (33 p.); 30 cm. (Box 5, Folder 65)
        Holograph in ink, corrections in liquid paper and pencil.
        Choral score for SATB chorus.